# STEVEN SOUTHARD

# FRONT-END/EMAIL DEVELOPER

### INTRODUCTION:

I create professionally designed HTML email templates and web pages to help your brand connect with customers. This can involves creating strategy, designing templates, and front-end development for both email and websites. Using nearly two decades of web and email industry experience, I can help your company expand its current marketing possibilities.

Expert-level knowledge of front-end web development using most CMS, Shopping cart systems, or email marketing platforms. Expert-level knowledge of all parts of sending mass emails which includes ESPs, CRMs, writing HTML/CSS for responsive emails, scripting, design, GDPR compliance, testing, troubleshooting, and deliverability. Expert at remote workflow.

## **CAPABILITIES:**

A reliable guide to developing a strategy for websites and email campaigns, writing front-end code, drawing mockups, hand-coding and scripting dynamic HTML and responsive templates, managing web and email template libraries, extending/managing databases, working with CMS, shopping carts, and email platforms, scripting with many templating languages, Litmus testing, using Photoshop, Fireworks, Illustrator, flexible to use any server setup, databases, languages, CMSs, CRM, email automation, and ESP.

Specialist for supporting advertisement, marketing and in-house design teams. Able to learn proprietary or new systems, quick to make use of existing data structures, adapt to code styles & standards. Some tools I've used are Apache Velocity, JavaScript, Ruby Radius Tags, Git, Heroku, s3, SQLite3 and MySQL, .NET, PHP, ASP, Java, Javascript, templating systems, and many more.

steven@stevensouthard.com (918) 815-9825

### **EXPERIENCE:**

CMS+Email Support Email Guide, 2019 to present

Support website and email campaigns for internet retail. Recent example web+branding using Shopify: Prairiebourne.com

Email Developer,

Clarion and Endeavor Business Media 2018 to 2020 (Remote, contract)

HTML email template development for eventrelated mass email campaigns

Email Template Developer+Design, PennWell 2013 to 2018 (Remote)

Template development for email marketing campaigns, eNLs, promotions, webcasts, white papers, and other kinds of business-related emails

Web Developer,

Littlefield Agency 2011 to 2012 (Tulsa, OK)

HTML, CSS, Javascript presentation layer and .Net SQL. Ditch Witch and YMCA Tulsa

Web & Email Developer, Marketing by Design 2008 to 2010 (Boston, remote)

HTML, UX design, Ruby on Rails, Radiant, Email newsletter and promotional email template development for TastyBite, Nasoya, and Nelson.

Web Developer,

Brookside Studio 2006 to 2007 (Tulsa, OK)

CSS, XHTML, PHP, Flash/Actionscript, UX design, project management, and client relations.

Studio Artist - 2003 to 2006 (Tulsa, OK)

Photography, screen printing, and production.

# **EDUCATION:**

Bachelor of Science Northeastern State, 1995 (Tahlequah, OK)